（駿海(しゅんかい)）２勝目
Their second win.
Eiga High is the first to get
a glimpse of the finish line.
（駿海）先に優勝に
王手をかけたのは 栄大(えいだい)か
Odachi can't afford another loss.
（柴木山(しばきやま)）
大太刀(おおだち)は もう負けられないですね
（大和国(やまとくに)）
熱戦が続いているようですね
It seems the bouts are being hotly contested.
Oh, you came,
おう 来たか　大和国
Yamatokuni.
It's been a long time.
（大和国）ご無沙汰しております
駿海さん 柴木山親方
Shunkai-san. Master Shibakiyama.
So is the Heisei era's greatest yokozuna
here to watch his son's victory?
（柴木山）平成の大横綱も
やはり 息子の大一番は気になるか
That's partly why, yes, but...
（大和国）それもありますが
この目で見たくなったんですよ
I wanted to see them with my own eyes...
相撲の未来を担う若者たちを
The young men who are
the future of sumo wrestling.
Fourth bout.
（アナウンス）副将戦 東 小関(おぜき)君
（小関）よし！
On the east side, Ozeki-kun.
Okay.
On the west side, Daniel-kun.
（アナウンス）西 ダニエル君
（ダニエル）いきます！
Here I go.
Oh, it's the blond sumo wrestler!
（男性Ａ）おお　出たな 金髪力士
（男性Ｂ）ダニエル　頑張れ！
You can do it, Daniel!
He's got such a cute smile!
（女性）笑顔が かわいい！
（ダニエル）うん？
（礼奈(れいな)）なに？　すごい人気
What's going on? The crowd's gone wild.
（千鶴子(ちづこ)）
学生相撲で白人系の選手は—
I believe it is partly due to there being
so few Caucasians in school sumo,
珍しいというのも
あると思うんですけど—
何より
この大会での活躍でしょうね
but his performances in the
tournament is a major factor, too.
He may not have won
the individual tournament,
個人戦では全国を逃(のが)しましたが—
but I hear he gave a good account
of himself against Kuze-san.
久世(くぜ)さんと
いい勝負をしたと評判です
For real?
マジ？
His physique is flawless.
（千鶴子）体格も文句なし
プロも注目の外国人力士です
Even the pros are watching
the progress of this foreigner.
He's in the same boat as Bat.
（天王寺(てんのうじ)）バトと同じやな
Foreigners can't attain
national treasure monikers,
外国人やから “国宝”とは
決して呼ばれへんが—
but he's pretty much on the same level.
その実力は国宝級って話や
Our secret weapon from Europe.
（兵藤(ひょうどう)）
ヨーロッパから来た秘密兵器
I've nicknamed him...
（兵藤）俺はヤツを
聖剣エクスカリバーと呼んでいる
the Holy Sword, Excalibur!
（四方田(よもだ)）お前だけな
Only you call him that.
As good as a national treasure...
（典馬(てんま)）
国宝級…　小関には荷が重いかもな
He may be more than Ozeki can handle.
Captain, stay level-headed.
You're good at that.
（火ノ丸(ひのまる)）部長　いつもどおり
落ち着いていくんじゃぞ
It's strange...
（千鶴子）なんか
団体戦の潮(うしお)君って いつも—
Ushio-kun always stands squarely behind
みんなの後ろで どっしり
構えてるイメージでしたけど—
his teammate in the ring
during team tournament bouts.
How should I put it?
何というか 優しいというか…
I guess I mean... it seems a kind thing to do.
（男性Ａ）おお〜！
やっぱり並ぶと すごい身長差！
When they're next to one another,
you can see how much taller he is!
Now isn't the time to compare physiques.
今更ですよね 体格差なんて
Sumo is about spirit.
“相撲は心”
You said that before the match.
あなた 試合前に言いましたね
僕も そう思います
I think so, too.
あなたたち 小さいけど
とても強いし
Your team is small, but very strong.
I'm big, but I used to be very weak.
僕も大きいけど とても弱かった
I came to Japan because I liked sumo.
でも 相撲が好きで 日本に来ました
I used to be weak, too.
俺も弱かったよ
I didn't win a single bout until last year.
去年まで 試合で勝ったこと
一度もなかったしね
おお！　弱いね
Wow, that's seriously weak.
Yeah, but...
（小関）うん　でも…
（ダニエル）うん？
強くなった
I'm stronger now.
So am I.
僕もです　僕たち
似た者同士かもしれませんね
In that sense, we are similar.
ハハハッ…　どうかな
Maybe so.
He's so passionate about sumo, he moved
to a different continent just to do it.
相撲のために 海を渡るほどの情熱
I've heard sumo's getting
more popular overseas,
海外での相撲人気も
上がってるっていうけど—
but it still takes a lot of courage
to decide to take it up.
相撲という競技を選ぶのは
まだまだ勇気が要るはず
I think you love sumo the same way I do.
きっと あなたも僕と同じで
相撲が大好き
And you got stronger for the exact
same reason I did, I'm sure of it!
そして 強くなった理由も—
きっと 同じ！
（審判）はっきよい！
Spirit!
（ダニエルたち）ンンッ！
Slap strikes.
（典馬）張り差し！
He's unrelenting!
止まらない！
Bout 23
"Spirit"
"Stronger now," huh?
〝強くなった〞か
It's true. Daniel used to be weak.
確かに
ダニエルは弱かった
（狩谷(かりや)）ンンッ！
（ダニエル）クッ…
We had high hopes for
the exchange student,
（四方田）
期待の留学生がフタを開ければ—
but when we saw him in action,
he was just some beefed-up sumo fanatic.
ただの でかいだけの相撲オタク
For sure, he had a huge frame,
そのでかい図体(ずうたい)の生かし方も
まるで分かっていなかった
but he didn't have a clue how to use it.
That Left-Arm Clamp looks
almost exactly like yours.
似てるな あの左四つ
お前の相撲に そっくりだ
Everyone doing sumo wrestling right now
僕らの世代で
相撲をやってるヤツは—
learned about the sport
from watching Yamatokuni.
みんな 大和国を見て
相撲を知ったんだ
Wanting to be like him
大和国みたいになりたくて
そのためなら—
was reason enough to go to
a sumo club in the next town over.
遠くの町の相撲クラブに通うのも
全然 苦じゃなくて
Was it the same for you?
君も そうだったのか？
海の向こうで
大和国のマネをした？
Were you there on another continent,
trying to copy Yamatokuni?
You're doing Yamatokuni's signature move:
the Left-Arm Clamp.
大和国 必殺の型 左四つ！
But I won't let you!
させない！　左上手は取らせない！
I won't let you seal my left arm!
I'm sure it's less that he's copying my move
私に似ているというより
あれは 草介(そうすけ)の影響でしょう
and more that he got it from Sosuke.
Hang in there, captain!
（千比路(ちひろ)）耐えろ 部長！
（桐仁(きりひと)）
自分の組み手になるまで我慢だ！
Grind it out until you can grab him!
Grind it out... In a battle of patience...
我慢だ
我慢比べなら 誰にも負けない！
I can beat anyone!
What mental strength!
心の強さ…
I have no doubt that your spirit
is every bit as strong as Onimaru's!
確かに あなたの心は
まるで鬼丸(おにまる)です
（小関）潮が教えてくれたんだ
Ushio opened my eyes
相撲の本当の面白さ
to the thing that makes
sumo truly enjoyable!
Captain.
（火ノ丸）部長
（小関）うん？
Go win this.
（火ノ丸）勝てよ
Tasting the joys of victory
（小関）
勝つ喜びを知って 俺は何倍も—
has made me love sumo all the more!
相撲が好きになったんだ！
（四方田）
本当に似てるのかもな この２人は
They might really be two peas in a pod.
どっちも
ちょっと前まで 本当に弱くて
They were both weaklings up until recently.
でも 互いに出会ったんだ
But both of them met a person
who changed them completely.
（四方田）
自分を変える存在 ヒーローに
They met their heroes.
（男性）小関！
（女性）ダニエル！
Ozeki!
Daniel!
（小関）我慢だ　焦らず じっくり
Grind it out.
Nice and steady.
（ダニエル）
上手(うわて)を取ったら 僕は強い！
If I can get my arm outside his,
I can overpower him!
I need to get my right arm on
the outside like he taught me!
（ダニエル）彼から学んだ右上手！
Eiga
University
High
School
Sumo
Club
I crossed the seas
just to do what I love.
憧れだけで海を渡った
I thought I could become a pro sumo wrestler.
大相撲力士になれると思ってた
But I got a cold, hard dose of reality.
でも 現実は甘くなかった
I can't beat anyone!
（ダニエル）勝てない！
みんな 僕より小さいのに
But why? I'm bigger than everyone here...
相撲 楽しくない
Sumo... isn't fun.
After spending my first year
thinking like that, I met him.
（ダニエル）彼を初めて見たのは
そんな１年の終わりごろ
He was still in middle school
彼は まだ中３で
and was coming to Eiga High
the following year,
来年 栄大に入ることが
既に決まっていたようだが—
but the club members at the time at least
didn't seem very welcoming.
少なくとも 当時は
あまり歓迎されていないようだった
They say he refuses to contest actual bouts.
（部員Ａ）
あいつ 試合には出ないんだと
Huh? What's up with that?
（部員Ｂ）ああ？　何だ？　そりゃ
お高くとまってらぁ
Does he think he's better than us?
I didn't know who he was.
（ダニエル）
彼が何者かは知らなかった
But when I fought him,
I couldn't help blurting out...
でも 僕は 彼と向かい合って
思わず つぶやいた
Y-Yamatokuni!
や… 大和国
Later on, they told me who he was,
（ダニエル）あとで
彼が何者かを聞かされたが—
そのときは驚くより納得した
and instead of being shocked,
it made total sense to me.
You're incredible.
（ダニエル）君は すごいですね
I'm sure sumo's a lot of fun
when you're as strong as you are.
君くらい強ければ
相撲も きっと楽しいでしょう
So much fun that you don't care
what other people say.
周りの声も気にならないくらい
（久世）う〜ん…
気になりますよ　僕も周りの声は
Hmm...
I do care about what other people say.
大和国の息子として
恥ずかしくない相撲が取れているか
I worry about whether my sumo
lives up to the Yamatokuni name.
そして そんなことが気になるのも
僕が弱いからだ
And worrying about that
shows that I'm weak.
（久世）本当は もっと
周りなど気にならないほど—
I need to focus my full attention on
the sumo ring and tune out what people say.
土俵に集中しないといけないんです
To do otherwise would be rude to
my opponent and to sumo as a whole.
だって それは 相手にも
相撲にも失礼なことですから
Do you enjoy sumo?
あなたは相撲 楽しいですか？
Hmm...
（久世）う〜ん…　相撲は好きです
でも 楽しいかと聞かれると…
I do like sumo.
But as for whether I enjoy it...
I don't know.
分かりません　僕には…
I have nothing...
相撲以外ないですから
必死にやるだけです
except sumo.
I must devote myself to it.
I felt like he was telling me
how naïve I was being.
（ダニエル）お前は甘いのだと
言われているような気がした
相撲を生業(なりわい)にしようとする者の覚悟
That was the mindset of a guy
trying to make sumo his livelihood.
Because I was so weak, I decided
to train harder than him.
弱い僕は
彼より少し多く しこを踏もう
If he did 300 stomps, I'd do 400!
彼が300回踏むなら 僕は400！
If that wasn't enough...
これでダメなら 諦めもつく！
I'd know it was time to give up!
Daniel. Sosuke. Starting today,
（四方田）ダニエル　草介
君たち２人
今日から １軍の土俵で稽古ね
you're training in the first-string ring.
And now, I enjoy sumo so much...
（ダニエル）僕は今
相撲が楽しくて 楽しくて—
So very, very much!
しかたがないんだ！
He couldn't grab him,
so he switched to strikes!
（男性Ａ）
組めないと見るや 突き押し！
Even at a distance, he's a beast!
（男性Ｂ）離れても強い！
（女性）キャ〜！
Your rapid improvement proves that
sumo is all about spirit.
（四方田）お前の急成長を見てると
つくづく思うよ
相撲は心だと
Yeah, Sosuke was on the third string
and being treated like an outcast.
確かに 草介は
３軍の土俵で疎まれていた
そんな中で ダニエルだけが
何度も何度も草介に挑み続けた
Daniel was the only one
who kept challenging him.
疎ましく思うヤツらは その程度
Those who froze him out didn't get very far.
草介と毎日 相撲が取れることを
チャンスと思えたヤツが—
And those who saw being able to spar with
Sosuke every day as a golden opportunity
now turn out for Eiga's first string.
今の栄大の１軍なのさ
So you get struck harder
than that every day?
（ダニエル）
もっと強い突きを毎日受けてきた
…とでも言いたげですね！
Is that what you're telling me?
Go, Ozeki!
（佑真(ゆうま)）いけ！　小関！
まるで ひと足早い鬼丸対草薙(くさなぎ)だ
This is like a sneak preview
of Onimaru versus Kusanagi.
なら 勝ってやらんとな
That means he has to win.
（小関）
潮が久世に勝とうとしてるんだ
Ushio wants to beat Kuze.
Which means I can't lose
to Kuze's style of sumo!
俺が ここで 久世の相撲に
負ける姿は見せられない！
よし！　部長の形！
Good, the captain's in position!
Wait for him to move forward,
then go for the outside.
（ダニエル）
前進する瞬間を狙って上手を取る！
僕のリーチなら届く！
I can reach around him!
I'm weak, so I'm always in fear of losing.
僕は弱いから
いつもヒリヒリしている
Ozeki-san, have I struck
at least a little fear in you?
小関さん　僕は あなたを
ヒリヒリさせてますか！？
Are you having fun right now?!
（ダニエル）
あなたは今 楽しいですか！？
右上手投げ 大蛇断(おろちだち)！
Right overarm throw!
Great Serpent Cleaver!
Great
Cleaver
Serpent
Daniel, you said we're similar,
but you're wrong.
（小関）ダニエル
君は俺たちが似てるって言ったけど
やっぱ違うよ
Your goal seems to be imitating Kuze,
君は久世になりたいみたいだけど
俺と潮は そうじゃないから！
but me and Ushio are nothing like that!
It was only once out of the hundreds
or thousands of times we sparred,
（小関）何千何百と取ったうちの
たった１回だけど—
俺 潮に勝ったことがあるんだ
but I actually beat Ushio.
俺は うれしくて
帰りにケーキを買っちゃって
I was so happy, I treated myself to cake.
潮は次の日も ムッとしてて
The next day, Ushio was still pouting.
And that made me happy, too.
それが また うれしくて
だって 俺と潮は…
Because me and Ushio... are rivals!
ライバルだから！
（歓声）
（千比路）部長！
Captain!
You did it!
（佑真）やったぜ！
（桐仁）よっしゃ！
Yes!
（蛍(けい)）部長ーっ！
Captain!
On the east side,
with a beltless arm throw...
（審判）
すくい投げで 東 小関君の勝ち！
Ozeki-kun wins!
He's got what it takes to be a national
treasure, but he still needs work.
素材は国宝級だが 粗削りか
いや ここは素直に
小関の辛抱強さを認めよう
No, I should take nothing away from Ozeki
and the patience that won him the bout.
It's 2-2 now.
これで２勝２敗
I've done all I can do.
俺がしてやれるのは ここまでだ
Now...
あとは お前が勝つだけだぜ
It's time for you to win, Ushio!
大将！
Team tournament final, fifth bout.
（アナウンス）団体戦
決勝 大将戦 東 潮君
On the east side, Ushio-kun.
On the west side, Kuze-kun.
西 久世君
（歓声）
Onimaru Kunitsuna and the Kusanagi Sword.
（男性Ａ）鬼丸国綱(くにつな)と草薙剣(くさなぎのつるぎ)
Two national treasures will slug it out
to decide the winner of the team tournament.
（男性Ｂ）団体優勝の行方は
２人の国宝に委ねられた！
That's not all that's at stake.
（柴木山）それだけじゃない
（大和国）“付出(つけだし)資格”
This bout may well be their ticket
to joining the pro league via entry into
the All-Japan National Championships.
プロ入りを懸けた
全日本選手権への出場権ですか
Listen to that crowd.
この歓声
今や誰もが 彼の力を認めている
Everyone already acknowledges his ability.
Even if he doesn't make it this year,
たとえ この機を逃しても 彼なら
いずれプロになれるでしょう
it's only a matter of time before he goes pro.
（駿海）違(ちげ)えよ
You've got it all wrong.
He doesn't just want to be a pro.
あいつはプロになりたいんじゃねえ
横綱になりてえのさ
He wants to be a yokozuna.
He doesn't have an unlimited
number of chances.
チャンスは無限にあるもんじゃねえ
ここで勝てねえで なにが横綱よ
How does he expect to become
a yokozuna if he doesn't win today?
Guys...
（火ノ丸）みんな
（一同）うん？
（火ノ丸）相撲は楽しかったか？
Did you enjoy doing sumo?
Yuma.
（火ノ丸）佑真
（佑真）うん？
（火ノ丸）
お前の真面目さ 紳士さは—
Your steady, earnest efforts
kept the sumo club going.
この相撲部を引き締めてくれた
Chihiro.
（火ノ丸）千比路
お前の勝者としての経験は—
Your experience as a champion
instilled confidence in the team.
この相撲部に 確かな自信を
Kirihito.
桐仁　お前は
進むべき道を示してくれた
You put us on the right path.
蛍　お前もじゃ
お前の勇気は相撲部を奮い立たせた
Kei.
We can't forget you.
Your courage inspired us all.
Hori-chan. Reina.
堀(ほり)ちゃん　礼奈
We've all seen the incredible
job you do in supporting us.
２人が裏で支えてくれたのも
ワシらは ちゃんと見とったからな
部長
３年間 相撲部を守り抜き—
Captain.
You protected the sumo club for three years,
クセの強いメンバーを束ねて
支えてくれて ありがとう
and united team members
with strong personalities.
Thank you for supporting us.
I'm glad you all joined the sumo club
and got enjoyment out of sumo.
みんな　相撲部に入ってくれて—
相撲を好きになってくれて
ありがとう
Thank you.
（佑真）ハハハッ…　バ〜カ
（火ノ丸たち）うん？
Idiot.
（佑真）礼を言いてえのは
こっちのほうなんだよ
We're the one who are grateful.
Thanks to you, we all learned to love sumo.
お前のおかげで
みんな 相撲を好きになったんだ
This is our last sumo bout as a team.
これが
このチームで取る最後の相撲だ
悔いは残すなよ
Don't leave with any regrets.
Go win this, Ushio!
勝ってこい 潮！
（火ノ丸）おう！
Yeah!
You won't win.
勝てっこねえさ
あいつは
相撲の神に選ばれた神の化身だ
The sumo gods have taken up
residence inside him.
Sosuke!
（狩谷）草介
This feeling again... I rather like it.
（久世）
まただ　悪くない この感覚
This silence engulfs us, as if we are
the only two people in the world.
この世界に
２人しかいないかのような静けさ
全てを忘れて 相撲に没頭できる
I can forget everything else
and just do sumo.
Hey.
（火ノ丸）おい
（久世）うん？
You don't want to hear it?
聞かねえってのかい？　この歓声を
You don't want to hear these cheers?
I came here so I could
hear this sound again.
（火ノ丸）これをまた聞きたくて
ワシは ここに来たってのによ
騒げ もっと
Louder...
Even louder...
Loud enough to reach the heavens!
（火ノ丸）雲の上にも届くくらいに
（久世）なるほど　君らしい
I see. That's how you do things.
（火ノ丸）
ずっと この時を待っていた
I've been waiting for this for a long time.
Yeah. So have I.
（久世）ああ　僕もだ
We started our bout that day...
（久世）あのときの勝負の続きを
...and today is the day we end it.
（火ノ丸）決着をつける
Now, let's put everything on the line.
さあ 命のやり取りをしよう
He was smiling until
he stepped into the sumo ring.
土俵に上がるまでは
笑ってたのにね
（天王寺）結びの一番
Their bout of destiny.
At last.
（駿海）いざ！
Spirit!
（審判）はっきよい！
A spider stance.
（柴木山）
平蜘蛛(ひらぐも)　揺らめくこと 火のごとし
Flickering
like fire.
（火ノ丸）
ずっと この時を待っていた！
I've waited so long for this!
（狩谷）あっ…
（佑真）よし！
Yes!
After the charge...
（桐仁）立ち合いは…
（千比路）鬼丸だ！
...Onimaru's on top!
Go!
（蛍･礼奈）いけー！
The do-or-die bouts I've survived,
（火ノ丸）幾多の死線を
くぐり抜けた経験が—
the strong opponents I've devoured,
強者を食らい
再び積み上げた自信が…
and the confidence I've rebuilt...
kindle my fire ever more!
ワシの炎をあおる！
（柴木山）溜(た)め？　正面突破！
He's loading up and attacking head-on!
I'm not just rushing in head-on!
ただ正面から行くんじゃねえ！
狙いを定めて 一点突破！
I'm choosing my target
and focusing on it!
That's the rising strike Tennoji used.
（四方田）
天王寺が見せた下からの突き上げ！
It's working!
効いてる！
Kuze is quick on his feet!
（桐仁）久世には速さがある！
（千比路）逃がすな！
Don't let him get away!
I know an even faster sumo wrestler!
もっと速い力士を
ワシは知っている！
Don't underestimate him just
because he has a short reach.
（駿海）
リーチがねえからと ナメるなよ
懐に入れば
火ノ丸の突きは強力な武器だ
Once he gets in close,
Hinomaru's strikes are a powerful weapon.
Having shorter arms
means he can strike faster.
その腕の短さが生む回転力で—
He even held his own against Odenta,
the most powerful striker in high school sumo.
高校一の突き押し
大典太(おおでんた)とも打ち合った
If he catches you when you're off-balance,
each strike he delivers
（典馬）崩れた体勢で受けきるには
その１発１発…
（火ノ丸）ンッ！
（典馬）見た目以上に重い！
hits harder than it looks.
おいおいおい！
草薙が もう土俵際！？
Hey, hey, hey!
Kusanagi's been forced back
to the edge of the ring?!
I could never have gotten this far on my own.
ワシ１人なら
ここまで上ってこれなかった
Go!
いけー！
（火ノ丸）
でも みんながいたから…
But my team was there for me!
Push!
押せー！
We've taken everything
fate could throw at us,
（火ノ丸）険しい道程も越えて
ここまで来たぞ！　久世草介！
and overcome it all to get here,
Kuze Sosuke!
In just a short amount of time,
（久世）
この短期間で 本当に強くなった
you have truly become strong.
But so have I.
お互いにね！
I will beat you and join the pro league.
君を倒して 僕は大相撲に行く
Kuze's every movement
is eroding my stamina...
久世の一挙一動が 肉体を…
精神をすり減らす
and my spirit.
If I make the wrong move even once...
ひとつでも対応を間違えたら 死…
I'm dead.
（久世）ンッ！
（火ノ丸）グアッ！
Hinomaru!
（礼奈）火ノ丸！
（火ノ丸）グッ…
Kuze never rushes or takes risks.
久世は焦らず 危険を冒さない
だから 攻めにも隙がない！
There are no holes in his offense!
止まるな！
横に動いて 揺さぶれ！
Don't stop!
Move off to the side to get him moving!
この高鳴りは 興奮？
それとも 恐怖？
This rush... Is it excitement?
Or is it fear?
Sosuke, what is a yokozuna?
（大和国）草介　横綱とは何だ？
Yamatokuni
Stable
One mistake in sumo
相撲は ひとつのミスが
取り返しのつかぬ致命傷となりうる
can turn out to be fatal.
だが 人間である以上
誰でもミスをする
But to err is human. We all make mistakes.
S
e
i
c
h
i
-
z
e
k
i
No matter how careful one might be.
どれだけ気をつけていてもだ
Champion
Y
o
k
z
u
n
a
Y
m
a
t
o
k
u
n
i
S
e
i
c
h
i
-
z
e
k
i
分かるか？　草介
横綱とは“恐れ 敬われる者”
Do you understand, Sosuke?
A yokozuna should be feared and respected.
To become a yokozuna,
you must crush all in your path.
横綱になるということは
勝ち続けるということ
To achieve that...
すなわち—
you must cease being human.
人間をやめるということだ
They're in a completely
different stratosphere.
次元が違い過ぎますよ…
That goes for both of them!
（ダニエル）２人ともね！
Not sideways!
横じゃねえ！　前へ！
Forward!
No, it's not working!
ダメだ　効かねえ！
なんで そこで前に踏み込める！？
How can he attack head-on in this situation?
Isn't he scared?
怖くねえのか？
Sure, I'm scared.
怖(こえ)えさ　久世も 相撲も
Scared of Kuze, of sumo... But even so...
でも…
（火ノ丸）ンッ！
（千比路）２連発！
Another strike!
...I'll step forward.
踏み込め！　目の前にあるんじゃ
横綱に限りなく近い何かが！
I can see it right in front of me...
An adversary who's so close
to being a yokozuna!
A victory that I'm willing
to risk my life for!
命を懸けてでも欲しい！　勝利が！
ウワッ！
A third strike!
３連発！
（久世）
何度 跳ね返しても諦めない
No matter how many times
I knock him back, he will not yield!
Yes. This is how you live.
そうだ　これが君の生き方だ
Your style of sumo.
君の相撲
Hinomaru's hands are inside!
（典馬）火ノ丸の下手(したて)！
（天王寺）草薙の上手！
Kusanagi's hands are outside.
They're both in the perfect range
for their killer move!
両者 必殺の間合い！
Heads together. Both hands on your belt.
（火ノ丸）頭をつけ 両前褌(りょうまえみつ)
I came up with this move in order to beat you!
元はといえば てめえに
勝つために編み出したんじゃ
Now, I'll keep shaking you and never stop!
ここから無限の揺さぶりが始まる
This is the move I've developed to win!
これが
たどりついたワシの必殺の型
I won't give you a chance
to start your motion.
（久世）好きに暴れさせはしない
これでも十分に力は出せる
I can still fight back from this position.
My father taught me
this right overhand grip.
父から譲り受けた右上手　天命の型
The move that defines my destiny.
Even one...
（火ノ丸）一瞬でも…
（久世）気を抜けば…
...moment's hesitation...
...and I'll lose!
（２人）殺(や)られる！
（礼奈）女子マネ同士で
相撲ごっこしていたら—
The two managers were giving sumo a whirl,
and Hinomaru saw us.
火ノ丸に見られた
パンツも見られた
He got an eyeful of panties, too.
Hinomaru's been acting strange ever since.
その日以来
火ノ丸の様子が おかしい
Um... Would... you two...
（火ノ丸）あ〜 その… ２人とも
（礼奈･千鶴子）うん？
N-No, never mind!
い… いや 何でもない！
何なの？　あいつ
何か私たちに言いたげだけど
What's gotten into him? It's like
he wants to tell us something.
ハッ…　まさか—
Could it be?
Are we now the objects of his desire,
私たちを異性として意識してしまい
欲情して 稽古に集中できないから
and he wants us to quit
our roles as club managers,
マネージャーを辞めてくれ
because we disrupt his concentration?
Is that the reason?
…という話では？
Where did that come from, Hori-chan?!
（礼奈）何言ってんの 堀ちゃん！
Listen, you! If you've got something
to say, just come right out and say it!
（礼奈）ちょっと あんた！
言いたいことあるなら
はっきり言いなさいよ！
ウッ…　なら 言うぞ
Okay... if you insist.
Reina, don't overstretch!
（火ノ丸）
礼奈　もっと上手は浅く　そう！
Better!
Hori-chan, you're doing well!
堀ちゃんも うまい！
これで投げを防ぐんじゃ
She can't throw you now!
I know you said to wipe that day from my
memory, but I couldn't get it out of my head!
いやぁ　あの日のことは
忘れろと言われたが—
どうしても気になってな
Odachi
High
School
Sumo
Club
Whaddaya say? How about
you both pick up sumo for real?
どうじゃ？　２人とも
これを機に
本格的に相撲を…
Next Bout    "The Dream Continues"
Odachi
High
School
Sumo
Club
（礼奈）やらない
No way.
Odachi
High
School
Sumo
Club
Odachi
High
School
Sumo
Club
Odachi
High
School
Sumo
Club
Odachi
High
School
Sumo
Club
Odachi
High
School
Sumo
Club
Odachi
High
School
Sumo
Club
Odachi
High
School
Sumo
Club
Odachi
High
School
Sumo
Club